<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>rizzplusplus</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 12:00:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>What to do when my friend betrayed my trust</title>
		<link>/what-to-do-when-my-friend-betrayed-my-trust/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=what-to-do-when-my-friend-betrayed-my-trust</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[wordpress]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2023 12:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Platonic relationship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1649</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Consent</title>
		<link>/consent/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=consent</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[albertw7711]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 05:58:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Romantic relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Consent]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://albertw7711.wordpress.com/?p=40</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Sexual consent is a crucial concept in any sexual encounter. It refers to the explicit agreement between all parties that would like to engage in a sexual act.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/consent/">Consent</a> first appeared on <a href="">rizzplusplus</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-full"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/consent.png" alt="examples of sexual consent" class="wp-image-1563"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Examples of consent (Source: Queensland Health)</figcaption></figure>



<div class="wp-block-uagb-advanced-heading uagb-block-437b3b83"><h2 class="uagb-heading-text">What is Consent?</h2></div>



<p>Sexual consent is a crucial concept in any sexual encounter. It refers to the explicit agreement between all parties that would like to engage in a sexual act. Consent is like ordering food at a restaurant; just like how you wouldn&#8217;t expect someone to order for you without asking if that&#8217;s what you want, you shouldn&#8217;t assume someone is willing to participate in sexual activity without asking for their explicit consent.</p>



<p></p>



<div class="wp-block-uagb-advanced-heading uagb-block-7e2a9341"><h2 class="uagb-heading-text">When do I need to give consent?</h2></div>



<p>Consent is an essential element of any healthy and safe sexual relationship, and it is a legal requirement in many jurisdictions. For example, in many states and countries, sexual activity without consent is considered sexual assault or rape and is punishable by imprisonment. Consent is getting a driver&#8217;s license; no consent, no sex.</p>



<p></p>



<div class="wp-block-uagb-advanced-heading uagb-block-ab117fce"><h2 class="uagb-heading-text">Who needs to give consent?</h2></div>



<p>Consent is a clear and enthusiastic agreement to participate in sexual activity. It is a voluntary choice that should not be influenced by coercion, threats, or force. For example, if someone threatens to break up with their partner unless they engage in sexual activity, that&#8217;s not considered consent because the decision was influenced by coercion. Similarly, consent obtained when the other party is not in a clear conscious state is not considered valid, such as when they are drunk.</p>



<p></p>



<div class="wp-block-uagb-advanced-heading uagb-block-0d66572d"><h2 class="uagb-heading-text">How to give consent?</h2></div>



<p>Consent must be given by all parties involved in the sexual encounter. It is not enough for one person to give consent on behalf of another. This means that both partners need to be actively involved in the discussion about sexual activities and be comfortable with the decisions made. Consenting is like signing a contract; just like how both parties need to agree and sign a contract to make it legally binding, both parties need to explicitly give consent to engage in sexual activity.</p>



<p>Consent should be given verbally and explicitly. It should not be assumed or implied. Non-verbal cues, such as body language or silence, cannot be considered consent. It is important to ask for consent and wait for a clear and enthusiastic response before engaging in any sexual activity. It is also important to be aware of the scope of the consent and the time during which it is valid. For example, being consented to having close physical contact does not mean being consented to engage in intercourse.</p>



<p></p>



<div class="wp-block-uagb-advanced-heading uagb-block-ece5b1fc"><h2 class="uagb-heading-text">Examples of consent</h2></div>



<p>Consent can be given in many ways, and it can vary from person to person. Here are some examples of how consent can be given:</p>



<ul>
<li>Verbal: &#8220;Yes, I want to have sex with you.&#8221;</li>



<li>Non-verbal: A nod, a smile, or a positive response to a sexual advance.</li>



<li>Conditional: &#8220;I&#8217;m comfortable with this sexual activity, but I don&#8217;t want to do anything else.&#8221;</li>



<li>Revoking consent: &#8220;I&#8217;m not comfortable with this anymore. I want to stop.&#8221;</li>



<li>Enthusiastic: &#8220;Yes! I&#8217;ve been wanting to do this with you for a long time.&#8221;</li>
</ul>



<p></p>



<div class="wp-block-uagb-advanced-heading uagb-block-da554d6e"><h2 class="uagb-heading-text">Why is consent important?</h2></div>



<p>Consent is essential for a safe and healthy sexual encounter. It is a fundamental human right that should be respected and upheld. Without consent, sexual encounters can become non-consensual, which can have severe physical and psychological consequences for all parties involved. Non-consensual sexual encounters are considered sexual assault or rape and are illegal in most jurisdictions. You have absolute right and ownership over your body. Just like your house, if you don’t want a person to enter it, he/she is not legally allowed to do so or it would be considered intrusion.</p>



<p></p>



<div class="wp-block-uagb-advanced-heading uagb-block-6a80ab44"><h2 class="uagb-heading-text">Conclusion</h2></div>



<p>In conclusion, sexual consent is a crucial element of any healthy and safe sexual relationship. It should be given explicitly, voluntarily, enthusiastically, and by all. If you want to learn more, please visit <a href="https://www.police.qld.gov.au/units/victims-of-crime/support-for-victims-of-crime/adult-sexual-assault/what-is-consent">Queensland Police Website</a> or <a href="https://www.rainn.org/articles/what-is-consent">Rape, Abuse &amp; Incest National Network</a> for more&nbsp;details. Remember, always say “NO” to any situation that makes you uncomfortable or puts you in risks of harm in anyway.</p><p>The post <a href="/consent/">Consent</a> first appeared on <a href="">rizzplusplus</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friendzone</title>
		<link>/friendzone/?utm_source=rss#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=friendzone</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[albertw7711]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 05:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Platonic relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Acceptance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Awkward]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Boundaries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Communication]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Friendzone]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Parasocial relationship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Physical intimacy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Respect]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Romance]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Toxic relationship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://albertw7711.wordpress.com/?p=48</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Friendzone is a term used to describe a situation where one person is interested in a romantic or sexual relationship with someone, but the other person only sees them as a friend. It can be a frustrating and confusing experience for the person who is interested in taking the relationship to the next level, and it can be equally challenging for the person who doesn't share the same feelings.</p>
<p>The post <a href="/friendzone/">Friendzone</a> first appeared on <a href="">rizzplusplus</a>.</p>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure class="wp-block-image aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/friendzone.jpg?w=323" alt="Friendzone logo - When a hearts meets a thumps up" class="wp-image-46"/></figure>



<p>Friendzone is a term used to describe a situation where one person is interested in a romantic or sexual relationship with someone, but the other person only sees them as a friend. A perfect example of parasocial relationship. It can be a frustrating and confusing experience for the person who is interested in taking the relationship to the next level, and it can be equally challenging for the person who doesn&#8217;t share the same feelings. In this article, we will explore the reasons for friendzoning, how to friendzone someone, what to do when the other person is persistent, how to get out of the friendzone, and what to do when you can&#8217;t get out of the friendzone.</p>



<p>Reasons for Friendzoning</p>



<p>There are several reasons why someone may friendzone another person. One common reason is that they are not physically attracted to the person. Physical attraction is an important aspect of a romantic relationship, and if someone doesn&#8217;t feel a physical spark with someone else, they may not be interested in pursuing a romantic relationship and want instead to set up a boundary. For example, imagine that you have a close friend who you&#8217;ve known for years, but you just don&#8217;t find them physically attractive. No matter how much they try to initiate a romantic relationship, you just can&#8217;t seem to get past the lack of physical attraction.</p>



<p>Another reason why someone may friendzone you is that they only see you as a friend. This can happen when someone values the friendship and connection they have with you, but they don&#8217;t want to take things to the next level. For instance, let&#8217;s say that you have a friend who you have a great time with, but you don&#8217;t feel that romantic spark. You friend, who greatly values the friendship between you two, will not want to risk losing it by trying to pursue a romantic relationship, hence setting up a boundary. Similarly, if you are the one who starts to have  romantic feelings towards your friend, he/she will not be willing to take it to the next level because things may get weird, awkward and in the worst-case scenario, it may not even be possible for you two to still be friends anymore.</p>



<p>How do you know if you have been Friendzoned?</p>



<p>There are several signs that can indicate that you have been friendzoned. One sign is that the other person only talks about their romantic or sexual interests with you, and they never initiate or show interest in pursuing a relationship with you. Another sign is that they may use phrases like &#8220;you&#8217;re such a good friend&#8221; or &#8220;I value our friendship too much to risk it by taking things further.&#8221; Additionally, if the other person avoids physical touch or intimacy, it may be a sign that they only see you as a friend.</p>



<p>How to Friendzone Someone</p>



<p>If you find yourself in a situation where you need to friendzone someone, it&#8217;s essential to be honest and clear about your feelings. Rememer, communication is always the key to achieve any relationship goal. One way to do this is to express your appreciation for their friendship and let them know that you don&#8217;t and won’t see them in a romantic or sexual way. Be gentle, but firm in your response to avoid any confusion or mixed signals. For example, you might say something like, &#8220;I really value our friendship, but I don&#8217;t see you in a romantic way. I hope we can continue to be good friends.&#8221;</p>



<p>What to Do When the Other Person is Persistent</p>



<p>If the other person is persistent and continues to pursue a romantic relationship despite your clear and honest communication, it&#8217;s important to set boundaries. Let them know that you are not interested in a romantic relationship, and that you need them to respect your feelings and boundaries. It can be challenging to deal with someone who is persistent, but it&#8217;s important to be firm and consistent in your communication. For example, you might say something like, &#8220;I understand that you have feelings for me, but I am not interested in a romantic relationship. I need you to respect my feelings and boundaries.&#8221; If he/she is till stubbornly persistent, you might consider create an additional layer of boundary by ghosting them.</p>



<p>Scenarios where a Person Should Take the Risk to Get Out of the Friendzone</p>



<p>There are situations where a person should take the risk to get out of the friendzone. For example, if the other person has recently ended a relationship or is going through a difficult time, they may be more receptive to the idea of a romantic relationship. Additionally, if there are signs that the other person may be interested in pursuing a relationship but is hesitant, it may be worth taking the risk and communicating your feelings. However, it&#8217;s important to be mindful of the other person&#8217;s feelings and respectful of their boundaries if they are not indeed interested.</p>



<p>Scenarios where a Person Shouldn&#8217;t Take the Risk to Get Out of the Friendzone</p>



<p>There are also situations where a person shouldn&#8217;t take the risk to get out of the friendzone. For example, if the other person is in a committed relationship or has made it clear that they are not interested in pursuing a romantic relationship, it&#8217;s important to respect their feelings and boundaries. Additionally, if pursuing a romantic relationship could jeopardize the friendship, it may be best to maintain the friendship and avoid taking the risk.</p>



<p>How to Get Out of the Friendzone</p>



<p>If you find yourself in the friendzone and you want to get out of it, the first step is to communicate your feelings to the other person. Let them know that you are interested in a romantic or sexual relationship and see if they feel the same way. If they don&#8217;t share the same feelings, it may be time to reevaluate your friendship and decide if it&#8217;s worth continuing as just friends. Sometimes it&#8217;s possible to get out of the friendzone and start a romantic relationship, but other times it&#8217;s best to accept that the other person doesn&#8217;t share the same feelings.</p>



<p>What to Do When You Can&#8217;t Get Out of the Friendzone</p>



<p>If you find yourself in a situation where you can&#8217;t get out of the friendzone, it&#8217;s essential to accept the other person&#8217;s feelings and move on. Being persistent or clingy won’t work! A romantic relationship only occurs when both sides have instinctive mutual feelings, and you can’t simply force it to happen.</p>



<p>Conclusion</p>



<p>In conclusion, friendzone is a complex and challenging experience that can be difficult to navigate. It&#8217;s essential for you to be honest and clear when communicating with others about your feelings while being respectful of their feelings and boundaries. Whether you&#8217;re trying to get out of the friendzone or trying to maintain a friendship, communication and mutual respect are key. By being mindful of these factors, you can navigate the friendzone with grace and compassion. If you believe you are really friends, you should be confident that they will understand you when you friendzone them and you should also make them confident that you will understand when they friendzone you, because that’s what a good, decent human, let along a real friend, will do.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="4686" height="3124" src="/wp-content/uploads/2023/04/platonic.jpeg?w=1024" alt="A woman hugging her male best friend" class="wp-image-47"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">If you are really good friends, there will be time when he/she needs you instead of their romantic parters. So be there for them.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Useful links</p>



<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-xPjsTyS4lY">An animation explaining friendzone by CasuallyExplained</a></p>



<p></p><p>The post <a href="/friendzone/">Friendzone</a> first appeared on <a href="">rizzplusplus</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
